[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements with respect to Endoplasmic Reticulum is incorrect?",
        "correct_answer": "In prokaryotes, ER is absent be it RER or SER.",
        "user_answer": "In prokaryotes only RER are present",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following plants shows vexillary aestivation and diadelphous stamens?",
        "correct_answer": "Pisum sativum",
        "user_answer": "Pisum sativum",
        "chapter": "Structural Organization in Plants and Animals"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fruit fly has 8 chromosomes (2n) in each cell. During interphase of Mitosis if the number of chromosomes at G1 phase is 8, what would be the number of chromosomes after S phase?",
        "correct_answer": "8",
        "user_answer": "8",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is present between the adjacent bones of the vertebral column?",
        "correct_answer": "Cartilage",
        "user_answer": "Cartilage",
        "chapter": "Structural Organization in Plants and Animals"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bilaterally symmetrical and acoelomate animals are exemplified by",
        "correct_answer": "Platyhelminthes",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Structural Organization in Animals"
    },
    {
        "question": "Osteoporosis is characterised by decreased bone mass and increased chance of fractures. Common cause of osteoporosis is increased levels of estrogen.",
        "correct_answer": "2",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are true for spermatogenesis but do not hold true for Oogenesis?",
        "correct_answer": "3",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following plants does not show plasticity?",
        "correct_answer": "Maize",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "Some dividing cells exit the cell cycle and enter vegetative inactive stage. This is called quiescent stage (G0). This process occurs at the end of",
        "correct_answer": "M phase",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "The body of the ovule is fused within the funicle at",
        "correct_answer": "Hilum",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Meiotic division of the secondary oocyte is",
        "correct_answer": "At the time of fusion of a sperm with an ovum",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements is correct?",
        "correct_answer": "2) Endocrine glands regulate neural activity and nervous system regulates endocrine glands",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following features is used to identify a male cockroach from a female cockroach?",
        "correct_answer": "Presence of caudal styles",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following never occurs during mitotic cell division?",
        "correct_answer": "Pairing of homologous chromosomes",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are found in extreme saline conditions?",
        "correct_answer": "Archaebacteria",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "I dentify the vertebrate group of animals characterized by crop and gizzard in its digestive system",
        "correct_answer": "Aves",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements with respect to Endoplasmic Reticulum is incorrect?",
        "correct_answer": "In prokaryotes, ER is absent be it RER or SER.",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the taxonomic categories which hierarchical arrangement in ascending order is correct  in case of animals?",
        "correct_answer": "Kingdom, Phylum, Class, Order, Family, Genus, Species",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "W hich one of the following plants shows a very close relationship with a species of moth, where none of the two can complete its life cycle without the other?",
        "correct_answer": "Yucca",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Not Available"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niche is",
        "correct_answer": "the functional role played by the organism where it lives",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appearance of recombination nodules on homologous chromosomes during meiosis characterizes :",
        "correct_answer": "Sites at which crossing over occurs",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Genetics and Evolution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the wrong  statement with reference to immunity.",
        "correct_answer": "Active immunity is slow and takes time to give its full effective response in comparison to passive immunity where pre-formed antibodies are administered.",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Immunity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements cannot be connected to Predation?",
        "correct_answer": "Both the interacting species are negatively impacted",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Ecology and Environment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the correct option.",
        "correct_answer": "mfpr fodYi dk p;u djks",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Human Anatomy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flowers which have single ovule in the ovary and are packed into inflorescence are usually pollinated by",
        "correct_answer": "Wind",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Habitat loss and fragmentation, over exploitation, alien species invasion and co -extinction are causes for:",
        "correct_answer": "Biodiversity loss",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following represents order of 'Horse'?",
        "correct_answer": "Perissodactyla",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the correct group of biocontrol agents.",
        "correct_answer": "Trichoderma, Baculovirus,  Bacillus thuringiensis",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Biology and Human Welfare"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following techniques, the embryos are transferred to assist those females who cannot conceive?",
        "correct_answer": "ZIFT and IUT",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following plants does not show plasticity?",
        "correct_answer": "Maize",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    }
]